<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-06-19T14:27:10+02:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">insert:view</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Cartoons for Adults? 5 Animated Shows Everyone Should Watch</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/alex.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cartoons for Adults? 5 Animated Shows Everyone Should Watch" /><published>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/alex</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/alex.html">&lt;p id=&quot;first-paragraph&quot; style=&quot;font-size: larger;left: 15%;padding-top: 25px;&quot;&gt;Everyone and I mean everyone, has a favourite cartoon. As children, these short form animated shows are handed to us in plenty as parents seek a moment of respite. But why keep them for the kids? Here are five cartoons, for both kids and adult, that will help you dive back into the creative colourful world of animation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-over-the-garden-wall&quot;&gt;1. Over the Garden Wall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cartoon Network’s 2014 mini-series Over the Garden Wall is a visual
spectacle,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;with every frame worthy of a gallery. Following half brothers Wirt
(Elijah Woods) and Greg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Collin Dean) as they find themselves lost in the Unknown and
unknowingly hunted by The&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beast, the show is the perfect blend of childish fun and uncanny
explorations more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;appreciated by older audiences. Much like the forest of the Unknown
itself, which stands&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;beautifully in the height of autumn, the show turns from kitsch to
creepy in a heartbeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-tuca-and-bertie&quot;&gt;2. Tuca and Bertie&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know of the much-too relatable Bojack Horseman, but from the same&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;producers comes Tuca and Bertie, an adult animated series that similarly
looks at deeper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ideas through the colourful and zany characters and style. The show
focuses on titular&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;best-friends Tuca and Bertie as they live their lives in the bustling
city of Bird Town; the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;two finding absolute joy in their friendship despite their differences
in character. Think&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girls as a well-done buddy comedy, but with a toucan and a thrush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-avatar-the-legend-of-korra-many-watched-the-first&quot;&gt;3. Avatar: The Legend of Korra (many watched the first)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not a stretch to say that many of us watched Nickelodeon’s Avatar:
The Last&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airbender growing up. The Legend of Korra is the fantastic follow-up to
the series that not&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;only recreates the feel of its predecessor but expands on its world in
fascinating ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Avatar, Korra, has to learn how to deal with the political and
spiritual unrest that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;comes with a new modernising world. What’s more, this show has
everything: gorgeous&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;fight sequences, well-developed characters, and both humour and emotion
aplenty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-archer&quot;&gt;4. Archer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This spy satire is one that’s well deserved of it’s long number of
seasons — it’s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;eleventh scheduled to be released this year. An all-out comedy, Archer
follows master spy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sterling Archer and the dysfunctional ‘International Secret Intelligence
Service’ he works&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for. Grounded primarily by it’s quick-witted dialogue and use of
self-referential humous,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the show isn’t afraid to be silly, instead going as far out-there as
possible to get a good&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;laugh. Though you may find yourself enjoying the later anthology seasons
more than&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;others, Archer is downright brilliant and bizarre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-she-ra-and-the-princesses-of-power&quot;&gt;5. She-Ra and the Princesses of Power&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be fooled by the glittery pastel visuals of this Netflix original,
underneath and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;alongside it is a show that looks at friendship, family, and war.
Following She-Ra and her&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;team coming up against foe and friend to take down oppressive empire,
The Horde, this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;show is the perfect blend of serious and fun. No matter what you’re in
the mood for, She-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ra will have it. Characters are multidimensional and the narrative
develops at a good&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pace, revealing layers of interest that give the show a real sense of
depth.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alex Dewing</name></author><category term="issue1" /><summary type="html">Everyone and I mean everyone, has a favourite cartoon. As children, these short form animated shows are handed to us in plenty as parents seek a moment of respite. But why keep them for the kids? Here are five cartoons, for both kids and adult, that will help you dive back into the creative colourful world of animation. 1. Over the Garden Wall Cartoon Network’s 2014 mini-series Over the Garden Wall is a visual spectacle, with every frame worthy of a gallery. Following half brothers Wirt (Elijah Woods) and Greg (Collin Dean) as they find themselves lost in the Unknown and unknowingly hunted by The Beast, the show is the perfect blend of childish fun and uncanny explorations more appreciated by older audiences. Much like the forest of the Unknown itself, which stands beautifully in the height of autumn, the show turns from kitsch to creepy in a heartbeat. 2. Tuca and Bertie We all know of the much-too relatable Bojack Horseman, but from the same producers comes Tuca and Bertie, an adult animated series that similarly looks at deeper ideas through the colourful and zany characters and style. The show focuses on titular best-friends Tuca and Bertie as they live their lives in the bustling city of Bird Town; the two finding absolute joy in their friendship despite their differences in character. Think Girls as a well-done buddy comedy, but with a toucan and a thrush. 3. Avatar: The Legend of Korra (many watched the first) It’s not a stretch to say that many of us watched Nickelodeon’s Avatar: The Last Airbender growing up. The Legend of Korra is the fantastic follow-up to the series that not only recreates the feel of its predecessor but expands on its world in fascinating ways. The new Avatar, Korra, has to learn how to deal with the political and spiritual unrest that comes with a new modernising world. What’s more, this show has everything: gorgeous fight sequences, well-developed characters, and both humour and emotion aplenty. 4. Archer This spy satire is one that’s well deserved of it’s long number of seasons — it’s eleventh scheduled to be released this year. An all-out comedy, Archer follows master spy Sterling Archer and the dysfunctional ‘International Secret Intelligence Service’ he works for. Grounded primarily by it’s quick-witted dialogue and use of self-referential humous, the show isn’t afraid to be silly, instead going as far out-there as possible to get a good laugh. Though you may find yourself enjoying the later anthology seasons more than others, Archer is downright brilliant and bizarre. 5. She-Ra and the Princesses of Power Don’t be fooled by the glittery pastel visuals of this Netflix original, underneath and alongside it is a show that looks at friendship, family, and war. Following She-Ra and her team coming up against foe and friend to take down oppressive empire, The Horde, this show is the perfect blend of serious and fun. No matter what you’re in the mood for, She- Ra will have it. Characters are multidimensional and the narrative develops at a good pace, revealing layers of interest that give the show a real sense of depth.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Paradox of Faith</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/amelia.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Paradox of Faith" /><published>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/amelia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/amelia.html">&lt;p id=&quot;first-paragraph&quot; style=&quot;/*font-size: larger;*//*left: 15%;&quot;&gt;Franz Jägerstätter refuses to do what is required of him, brings shame
upon his family, provokes their persecution, and ultimately entirely
abandons them. He is also a devout Christian, and was beatified by the
Catholic Church in 2007. Watching Terrence Malick's *A Hidden Life*
(2019), we don't reproach Jägerstätter for his decisions. Instead, he
simultaneously amazes, perplexes and disconcerts us. He is a Christian
martyr much like Sir Thomas More in *A Man for All Seasons*, and yet his
name and story is largely unknown.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malick tells this forgotten story, and remains largely faithful to the
intricacies of Jägerstätter’s life. In the film, Jägerstätter (August
Diehl) is an Austrian farmer who leads a simple, bucolic existence
working the land and raising his three young daughters with his wife
Fani (Valerie Pachner). With the advent of the Second World War and the
Nazi annexation of Austria, Jägerstätter is conscripted along with
fellow men from the small tight-knit community of St. Radegund. Of the
few people in history to resist swearing the compulsory oath of
allegiance to Hitler, Franz Jägerstätter is one of them. He withstands
the persistent pressure, dissuasion and aggression from his fellow
villagers and even the local ecclesiastical figures. Inevitably, he is
imprisoned, and he and Fani write letters to one another while he awaits
his trial. He is found guilty of treason and sentenced to death. Fani is
allowed to visit Jägerstätter, and he is given a final chance to sign
the oath. He does not waver, and is executed by guillotine in 1943, just
months after his initial act of defiance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a relatively simple plot, but told beautifully. Various critics
have derided &lt;em&gt;A Hidden Life&lt;/em&gt; for its apparently yawn-inducing length
(the film is just under 3 hours long), but I can’t say that I agree. The
film bears a heavy philosophical weight, and the frequent scenes of the
Austrian landscape and general rural life serve as much-needed breathing
space. As a philosophy student, I hesitate to argue that any film is, or
can be, philosophy - but &lt;em&gt;A Hidden Life&lt;/em&gt; definitely gets as close as is
possible. Perhaps the long running time is part of that; anyone who has
tried to read philosophy will know that reading just 10 pages can take
hours (I’m looking at you, Kant).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how philosophers actually write, there is a general
consensus that philosophy ought to try, at least, to be concise and
clear. Terrence Malick has become infamous for his almost aggressively
non-linear and abstract style, but &lt;em&gt;A Hidden Life&lt;/em&gt; is different.
Remarkably, the film has a chronological narrative structure and a
precise plot. No rogue cosmological depictions of the origin of the
universe. No inexplicable shots of characters wandering away with their
backs to the camera. That said, there are plenty of voice-overs and the
usual unshakeable devotion to wide-angle lenses (16mm was the longest
lens used). It is a Terrence Malick film, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film’s philosophical content draws on the traditions of theistic
existentialism, fideism and Christian morality. To explain what these
theories mean, I will turn to the figure that unites all three: Søren
Kierkegaard. Malick read the 19th Century Danish philosopher extensively
when he was a philosophy student, and these readings have, without a
doubt, left a life-long impression on him. Indeed, Malick even sneaks in
a quotation by him in the script’s preface of &lt;em&gt;A Hidden Life&lt;/em&gt;, which I
will return to later. Of his many notable writings, it is Kierkegaard’s
discussion of faith and Abraham that serve as the visible theoretical
foundations for the film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the so-called ‘father of existentialism’, Kierkegaard emphasised the
absolute freedom of the individual - as given by God - to self-determine
in life. With absolute freedom, comes absolute responsibility. As
Jägerstätter profoundly asks a bishop, “If God gives us free will, we’re
responsible for what we do, what we fail to do, aren’t we?” The bishop
does not grant this: “You have a duty to the Fatherland, the Church
tells you so.” Jägerstätter suspects that the bishop takes him for a
Nazi spy, and so perhaps decided to avoid running the risk of
persecution. By this point, news has already spread that the Nazis are
sending Catholic clergy members to concentration camps. Regardless, when
faced with extreme evil, are we really as free to self-determine as
usual? When his defence attorney presents him with the oath, he tells
Jägerstätter, “Sign the paper and you’ll go free”. “But I am free,” he
replies. Freedom is absolute, an inalienable fact about the human
condition. Nevertheless, are we not compelled, morally, to condition our
behaviour in order to minimise the suffering of ourselves and those we
love? Rationally speaking, it would seem so. Religiously speaking, it
would depend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to fideism, faith is independent of reason. For Kierkegaard,
faith cannot and should not be rationalised or arrived at by
philosophical argument or evidence. Faith involves objective
uncertainty, but subjective certainty; faith is incomprehensible, but
not nonsense. A film that brilliantly captures this nuance is &lt;em&gt;A Man for
All Seasons&lt;/em&gt;, especially during a specific conversation between Sir
Thomas More (Paul Scofield) and his daughter Meg (Marah Stohl). Meg
tries to persuade her imprisoned father to swear the Act of Succession,
to consent to Henry VIII’s divorce from Catherine of Aragon, an act
wholly against More’s Catholic faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;More: …But look now, if we lived in a State where virtue was
profitable, common sense would make us saintly. But since we see that
avarice, anger, pride and stupidity commonly profit far beyond
charity, modesty, justice and thought, perhaps we must stand fast a
little, even at the risk of being heroes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meg: But in reason! Haven’t you done as much as God can reasonably want?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More: Well, finally it isn’t a matter of reason. Finally, it’s a matter
of love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jägerstätter is not as erudite nor as eloquent as More, but they both
possess this unconditional faith in God that is almost impossible to
comprehend for those around them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Fear and Trembling&lt;/em&gt;, Kierkegaard introduces another man of faith, or
rather, ‘the father of faith’ himself: Abraham. The book examines the
biblical story of God’s test of Abraham, wherein Abraham is asked to
sacrifice his adored son Isaac. He neither hesitates nor questions, but
simply sets about to kill his son as instructed. Luckily, God intervenes
just as Abraham reaches for the knife, and Isaac’s life is spared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Kierkegaard, Abraham’s story shows the paradoxical, incomprehensible
nature of faith. Abraham is not a tragic hero, but either a
schizophrenic murderer or a man of faith. In trusting God, he acts ‘on
the strength of the absurd.’ In Kierkegaard’s philosophy, there are
three stages to life: the aesthetic, the ethical and the religious. In
brief, the aesthetic is characterised by sensory experiences and
pleasures. With maturity, one transcends this stage to the ethical. This
involves living in accordance with higher ‘ethical’ principles and
rules. The superior stage, the religious, demands total faith in God.
Kierkegaard admits that for most people, including himself, the ‘leap of
faith’ from the ethical to the religious stage is too difficult a jump.
Abraham completes his leap through committing, unwaveringly, to
sacrificing his son as per God’s orders. Indeed, it involves a
‘teleological suspension of the ethical.’ This is Kierkegaard’s fancy
way of saying that Abraham has complete confidence in God’s commands,
despite their ethically suspicious nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kierkegaard does not wish to say that all Christians live at this
superior stage of existence. In fact, he fiercely condemned the church
for ‘playing at Christianity’, and for contorting true faith into
something easily achievable. Going to church a lot, being sanctimonious,
evangelising, wearing a cross ≠ faith. Kierkegaard wanted to do away
with institutionalized Christianity and instead recognise the rarity of
genuine, true faith in God. In &lt;em&gt;A Hidden Life&lt;/em&gt;, Ohlendorff (Johan
Leysen), a painter who is restoring the frescos in the village church,
admits he only paints “their comfortable Christ.” He goes on: “We create
admirers. We do not create followers. Christ’s life is a demand. We
don’t want to be reminded of it.” This subtle criticism of the church is
in truly Kierkegaardian fashion; being a churchgoer or identifying as
Christian and having true faith are not two sides to the same coin. True
faith in God and acting according to Christ’s example, even if that
involves self-sacrifice and deep suffering, is intensely difficult.
Jägerstätter’s character is so impressive &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; he is a genuine
follower, and not simply an admirer. He is, perhaps, to Terrence Malick
what Abraham was to Kierkegaard. In both depictions of Jägerstätter and
Abraham, there is a tangible tinge of reverence and awe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sir Thomas More, just like Jägerstätter, was eventually executed by
decapitation. As men of great faith, they became Christian martyrs.
Malick was deeply interested in the subject of martyrdom in writing &lt;em&gt;A
Hidden Life&lt;/em&gt;. The Kierkegaard quotation mentioned earlier reads ‘The
tyrant dies, and his rule is over; the martyr dies, and his rule
begins’. Only in dying can one become a martyr, and yet in acquiring
martyrdom, one becomes immortal. Christianity easily lends itself to
martyr-making; it is handily equipped with the concepts of salvation and
heaven, wherein a Christian is promised a place to live eternally with
God and their loved ones. Jägerstätter hopes for this future with his
wife and family. Fani, too, believes she will meet him again “through
God’s grace.” Death will not mark the end for Jägerstätter, as
symbolised by a black caterpillar, crawling along his desk as he writes
letters from prison. Just as a caterpillar transforms its body and
becomes a butterfly, when his body dies, his soul will live on in
heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the close of the film, Malick gives the following quotation from
George Eliot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;'For the growing good of the world is partly dependent on unhistoric
acts; and that things are not so ill with you and me as they might
have been, is half owing to the number who lived faithfully a hidden
life, and rest in unvisited tombs.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The excerpt ties the film together nicely, contextualising the title and
focusing our eye on the subject of forgotten martyrs. But there is
another ‘hidden’ meaning in this too. The phrase ‘a hidden life’, both
as the chosen title and in George Eliot’s words, is most likely
referring to a certain Bible verse. In the rather neglected book of
Colossians, Paul wrote, ‘For you died, and your life is now hidden with
Christ in God’ (3:3).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although obscure, the quotation closely resembles Kierkegaard’s
philosophy. Namely, to have faith in God, and to die with this faith, is
in some sense ‘hidden’ to those who lack this. Non-Christians and
pseudo-Christians can only see those with true faith behind a veil of
incomprehension. Jägerstätter’s sister deems her brother’s defiance as
“pride,” and a neighbour calls it a “sin against his family…[and]
his village.” Many try to persuade Jägerstätter round, insisting that
his behaviour is needless, pointless: “Your sacrifice would benefit no
one”; “Nobody would know.” Yet Jägerstätter has faith in an all-seeing
God, from whom nothing can be hidden. No overt action nor covert thought
escapes God; Jägerstätter, along with every other human to exist, does
not and cannot lead a 'hidden life’ from God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Sources/Further Reading]{.underline}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kierkegaard, Søren. &lt;em&gt;Attack Upon Christendom&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kierkegaard, Søren. &lt;em&gt;Either/Or.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kierkegaard, Søren. &lt;em&gt;Fear and Trembling.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New International Version Bible&lt;/em&gt;. Colossians 3:3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amesbury, Richard, &quot;Fideism&quot;, &lt;em&gt;The Stanford Encyclopedia of
Philosophy&lt;/em&gt; (Fall 2017 Edition), Edward N. Zalta (ed.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McDonald, William, &quot;Søren Kierkegaard&quot;, &lt;em&gt;The Stanford Encyclopedia of
Philosophy&lt;/em&gt; (Winter 2017 Edition), Edward N. Zalta (ed.).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Amelia Deering</name></author><category term="issue1" /><summary type="html">Franz Jägerstätter refuses to do what is required of him, brings shame upon his family, provokes their persecution, and ultimately entirely abandons them. He is also a devout Christian, and was beatified by the Catholic Church in 2007. Watching Terrence Malick's *A Hidden Life* (2019), we don't reproach Jägerstätter for his decisions. Instead, he simultaneously amazes, perplexes and disconcerts us. He is a Christian martyr much like Sir Thomas More in *A Man for All Seasons*, and yet his name and story is largely unknown. Malick tells this forgotten story, and remains largely faithful to the intricacies of Jägerstätter’s life. In the film, Jägerstätter (August Diehl) is an Austrian farmer who leads a simple, bucolic existence working the land and raising his three young daughters with his wife Fani (Valerie Pachner). With the advent of the Second World War and the Nazi annexation of Austria, Jägerstätter is conscripted along with fellow men from the small tight-knit community of St. Radegund. Of the few people in history to resist swearing the compulsory oath of allegiance to Hitler, Franz Jägerstätter is one of them. He withstands the persistent pressure, dissuasion and aggression from his fellow villagers and even the local ecclesiastical figures. Inevitably, he is imprisoned, and he and Fani write letters to one another while he awaits his trial. He is found guilty of treason and sentenced to death. Fani is allowed to visit Jägerstätter, and he is given a final chance to sign the oath. He does not waver, and is executed by guillotine in 1943, just months after his initial act of defiance. It is a relatively simple plot, but told beautifully. Various critics have derided A Hidden Life for its apparently yawn-inducing length (the film is just under 3 hours long), but I can’t say that I agree. The film bears a heavy philosophical weight, and the frequent scenes of the Austrian landscape and general rural life serve as much-needed breathing space. As a philosophy student, I hesitate to argue that any film is, or can be, philosophy - but A Hidden Life definitely gets as close as is possible. Perhaps the long running time is part of that; anyone who has tried to read philosophy will know that reading just 10 pages can take hours (I’m looking at you, Kant). Regardless of how philosophers actually write, there is a general consensus that philosophy ought to try, at least, to be concise and clear. Terrence Malick has become infamous for his almost aggressively non-linear and abstract style, but A Hidden Life is different. Remarkably, the film has a chronological narrative structure and a precise plot. No rogue cosmological depictions of the origin of the universe. No inexplicable shots of characters wandering away with their backs to the camera. That said, there are plenty of voice-overs and the usual unshakeable devotion to wide-angle lenses (16mm was the longest lens used). It is a Terrence Malick film, after all. The film’s philosophical content draws on the traditions of theistic existentialism, fideism and Christian morality. To explain what these theories mean, I will turn to the figure that unites all three: Søren Kierkegaard. Malick read the 19th Century Danish philosopher extensively when he was a philosophy student, and these readings have, without a doubt, left a life-long impression on him. Indeed, Malick even sneaks in a quotation by him in the script’s preface of A Hidden Life, which I will return to later. Of his many notable writings, it is Kierkegaard’s discussion of faith and Abraham that serve as the visible theoretical foundations for the film. As the so-called ‘father of existentialism’, Kierkegaard emphasised the absolute freedom of the individual - as given by God - to self-determine in life. With absolute freedom, comes absolute responsibility. As Jägerstätter profoundly asks a bishop, “If God gives us free will, we’re responsible for what we do, what we fail to do, aren’t we?” The bishop does not grant this: “You have a duty to the Fatherland, the Church tells you so.” Jägerstätter suspects that the bishop takes him for a Nazi spy, and so perhaps decided to avoid running the risk of persecution. By this point, news has already spread that the Nazis are sending Catholic clergy members to concentration camps. Regardless, when faced with extreme evil, are we really as free to self-determine as usual? When his defence attorney presents him with the oath, he tells Jägerstätter, “Sign the paper and you’ll go free”. “But I am free,” he replies. Freedom is absolute, an inalienable fact about the human condition. Nevertheless, are we not compelled, morally, to condition our behaviour in order to minimise the suffering of ourselves and those we love? Rationally speaking, it would seem so. Religiously speaking, it would depend. According to fideism, faith is independent of reason. For Kierkegaard, faith cannot and should not be rationalised or arrived at by philosophical argument or evidence. Faith involves objective uncertainty, but subjective certainty; faith is incomprehensible, but not nonsense. A film that brilliantly captures this nuance is A Man for All Seasons, especially during a specific conversation between Sir Thomas More (Paul Scofield) and his daughter Meg (Marah Stohl). Meg tries to persuade her imprisoned father to swear the Act of Succession, to consent to Henry VIII’s divorce from Catherine of Aragon, an act wholly against More’s Catholic faith. More: …But look now, if we lived in a State where virtue was profitable, common sense would make us saintly. But since we see that avarice, anger, pride and stupidity commonly profit far beyond charity, modesty, justice and thought, perhaps we must stand fast a little, even at the risk of being heroes. Meg: But in reason! Haven’t you done as much as God can reasonably want? More: Well, finally it isn’t a matter of reason. Finally, it’s a matter of love. Jägerstätter is not as erudite nor as eloquent as More, but they both possess this unconditional faith in God that is almost impossible to comprehend for those around them. In Fear and Trembling, Kierkegaard introduces another man of faith, or rather, ‘the father of faith’ himself: Abraham. The book examines the biblical story of God’s test of Abraham, wherein Abraham is asked to sacrifice his adored son Isaac. He neither hesitates nor questions, but simply sets about to kill his son as instructed. Luckily, God intervenes just as Abraham reaches for the knife, and Isaac’s life is spared. For Kierkegaard, Abraham’s story shows the paradoxical, incomprehensible nature of faith. Abraham is not a tragic hero, but either a schizophrenic murderer or a man of faith. In trusting God, he acts ‘on the strength of the absurd.’ In Kierkegaard’s philosophy, there are three stages to life: the aesthetic, the ethical and the religious. In brief, the aesthetic is characterised by sensory experiences and pleasures. With maturity, one transcends this stage to the ethical. This involves living in accordance with higher ‘ethical’ principles and rules. The superior stage, the religious, demands total faith in God. Kierkegaard admits that for most people, including himself, the ‘leap of faith’ from the ethical to the religious stage is too difficult a jump. Abraham completes his leap through committing, unwaveringly, to sacrificing his son as per God’s orders. Indeed, it involves a ‘teleological suspension of the ethical.’ This is Kierkegaard’s fancy way of saying that Abraham has complete confidence in God’s commands, despite their ethically suspicious nature. Kierkegaard does not wish to say that all Christians live at this superior stage of existence. In fact, he fiercely condemned the church for ‘playing at Christianity’, and for contorting true faith into something easily achievable. Going to church a lot, being sanctimonious, evangelising, wearing a cross ≠ faith. Kierkegaard wanted to do away with institutionalized Christianity and instead recognise the rarity of genuine, true faith in God. In A Hidden Life, Ohlendorff (Johan Leysen), a painter who is restoring the frescos in the village church, admits he only paints “their comfortable Christ.” He goes on: “We create admirers. We do not create followers. Christ’s life is a demand. We don’t want to be reminded of it.” This subtle criticism of the church is in truly Kierkegaardian fashion; being a churchgoer or identifying as Christian and having true faith are not two sides to the same coin. True faith in God and acting according to Christ’s example, even if that involves self-sacrifice and deep suffering, is intensely difficult. Jägerstätter’s character is so impressive because he is a genuine follower, and not simply an admirer. He is, perhaps, to Terrence Malick what Abraham was to Kierkegaard. In both depictions of Jägerstätter and Abraham, there is a tangible tinge of reverence and awe. Sir Thomas More, just like Jägerstätter, was eventually executed by decapitation. As men of great faith, they became Christian martyrs. Malick was deeply interested in the subject of martyrdom in writing A Hidden Life. The Kierkegaard quotation mentioned earlier reads ‘The tyrant dies, and his rule is over; the martyr dies, and his rule begins’. Only in dying can one become a martyr, and yet in acquiring martyrdom, one becomes immortal. Christianity easily lends itself to martyr-making; it is handily equipped with the concepts of salvation and heaven, wherein a Christian is promised a place to live eternally with God and their loved ones. Jägerstätter hopes for this future with his wife and family. Fani, too, believes she will meet him again “through God’s grace.” Death will not mark the end for Jägerstätter, as symbolised by a black caterpillar, crawling along his desk as he writes letters from prison. Just as a caterpillar transforms its body and becomes a butterfly, when his body dies, his soul will live on in heaven. At the close of the film, Malick gives the following quotation from George Eliot: 'For the growing good of the world is partly dependent on unhistoric acts; and that things are not so ill with you and me as they might have been, is half owing to the number who lived faithfully a hidden life, and rest in unvisited tombs.' The excerpt ties the film together nicely, contextualising the title and focusing our eye on the subject of forgotten martyrs. But there is another ‘hidden’ meaning in this too. The phrase ‘a hidden life’, both as the chosen title and in George Eliot’s words, is most likely referring to a certain Bible verse. In the rather neglected book of Colossians, Paul wrote, ‘For you died, and your life is now hidden with Christ in God’ (3:3). Although obscure, the quotation closely resembles Kierkegaard’s philosophy. Namely, to have faith in God, and to die with this faith, is in some sense ‘hidden’ to those who lack this. Non-Christians and pseudo-Christians can only see those with true faith behind a veil of incomprehension. Jägerstätter’s sister deems her brother’s defiance as “pride,” and a neighbour calls it a “sin against his family…[and] his village.” Many try to persuade Jägerstätter round, insisting that his behaviour is needless, pointless: “Your sacrifice would benefit no one”; “Nobody would know.” Yet Jägerstätter has faith in an all-seeing God, from whom nothing can be hidden. No overt action nor covert thought escapes God; Jägerstätter, along with every other human to exist, does not and cannot lead a 'hidden life’ from God. [Sources/Further Reading]{.underline} Kierkegaard, Søren. Attack Upon Christendom. Kierkegaard, Søren. Either/Or. Kierkegaard, Søren. Fear and Trembling. New International Version Bible. Colossians 3:3. Amesbury, Richard, &quot;Fideism&quot;, The Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy (Fall 2017 Edition), Edward N. Zalta (ed.). McDonald, William, &quot;Søren Kierkegaard&quot;, The Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy (Winter 2017 Edition), Edward N. Zalta (ed.).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Childhood Sweetheart: A Look at My Favourite Hilary Duff Movies</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/fatima.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Childhood Sweetheart: A Look at My Favourite Hilary Duff Movies" /><published>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/fatima</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/fatima.html">&lt;p id=&quot;first-paragraph&quot; style=&quot;/*font-size: larger;*//*left: 15%;&quot;&gt;Hilary Duff has played a central role in my life since I was a child.
All I wanted was to live in a small suburban town and wear bandannas and pom-pom scrunchies in my hair like her and Lalaine in &lt;i&gt;Lizzie McGuire&lt;/i&gt;. When I think back to which mid-2000s celebrity's oeuvre I hold the most dear to my heart, the magical work of the Duff reigns supreme. Below, I share four of my favourite Duff films and the lasting impact they have had on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;raise-your-voice&quot;&gt;Raise Your Voice&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We begin with the 2004 box-office bomb, &lt;em&gt;Raise Your Voice&lt;/em&gt;. Full of
cringe-inducing musical performances and first kisses, this film is the
perfect introduction to the messy and hilarious genre of music-centered
romance movies of the 2000s (&lt;em&gt;High School Musical&lt;/em&gt; (2006) and &lt;em&gt;Camp
Rock&lt;/em&gt; (2008) being the obvious examples of when the genre perfected
itself). Hilary Duff plays Terri Fletcher, a sixteen-year-old living in
Flagstaff, Arizona, who dreams of becoming a singer. The film takes a
dark turn when her brother Paul is killed in a car accident, after a
Three Days Grace concert. Terri’s mother urges her to go to a music
conservatory on the West Coast over the summer, to follow her heart and
fulfil her late brother’s dreams for her. Once there, Terri tastes her
first slice of reality outside of her small-town upbringing: mean girls,
cute boys, and a competitive music school. What follows is a heartfelt
story about family and first romance, replete with saccharine dialogue
about ‘the transcendent power of music.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-lizzie-mcguire-movie&quot;&gt;The Lizzie McGuire Movie&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually the favourite of many Duff fans, &lt;em&gt;The Lizzie McGuire Movie&lt;/em&gt;
(2003) follows the characters of the titular television show as they
embark on their graduation trip to Rome. What begins as an innocent
school trip full of pizza and piazzas swiftly turns into a whirlwind
journey for Lizzie, who is pursued by Italian pop star Paolo due to her
uncanny likeness to his singing partner Isabella. Lizzie is roped into
performing with him (and pretending to be Isabella) at the Italian Music
Awards, throwing her into the glittering world of fame. As the story
unfolds, however, we realise Paolo may not be exactly who we thought him
to be. The movie is beautifully chaotic in its nonsensical storyline,
overflowing with excitement, intrigue, and a phenomenal soundtrack which
I still listen to. We also finally (finally!) have romance between
Lizzie and Good Guy Gordo, and for that, I am eternally grateful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-perfect-man&quot;&gt;The Perfect Man&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, &lt;em&gt;The Perfect Man&lt;/em&gt; is one of the Duff films that
unfortunately gets overshadowed by the rest, and is rarely lauded with
the praise it deserves. Set in Brooklyn, the film follows the lives of
single mother Jean (played brilliantly by Heather Locklear) and her two
daughters, Holly and Zoe. Sick of seeing her mother heartbroken over
another deadbeat man, Holly (Duff) decides to play matchmaker and set
her mother up with a fake ‘secret admirer’ named Ben, based off of her
friend’s restaurateur uncle (played by&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris Noth of &lt;em&gt;Sex and the City&lt;/em&gt; fame). As Holly struggles to keep the
secret of the matchmaking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;from her mother (with the help of artsy boy Adam played by Ben Feldman,
who I concede is a&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;big reason why I love this film so much), we see mother and daughter
deal with the ups&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and downs of romantic life. The film pushes beyond its own fluttery
romcom scope to become a testament to both family and womanhood.
Soundtracked to some beautiful 2000s melodies (and containing possibly
the happiest moment in cinematic history: all three women dancing to
Kaci Battaglia’s “I Will Learn to Love Again” in a living-room routine),
&lt;em&gt;The Perfect Man&lt;/em&gt; is a perfect feel-good movie I find myself coming back
to more often than I would care to admit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-cinderella-story&quot;&gt;A Cinderella Story&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last movie on my list is the 2004 cinematic triumph, &lt;em&gt;A Cinderella
Story&lt;/em&gt;. Set in a drought-ridden San Fernando Valley, Duff plays Sam
Montgomery, a teenage girl who lives with her emotionally abusive
stepmother and stepsisters and works at her late father’s diner after
school. The story is, of course, that of Cinderella, just with a few
more flip phones and low-rise jeans. As an escape from her tumultuous
home life, she finds refuge in an online pen pal ‘Nomad’, who is
secretly quarterback Austin Ames (played by none other than 2000s
heartthrob Chad Michael Murray). They finally meet at the Halloween
dance (where Austin is unable to recognise her because of a mask?)
before Sam rushes to get back to the diner by midnight. She accidentally
drops her cell phone while leaving the dance, thus prompting Austin to
find the identity of his mystery girl. The film explores ideas of
friendship, family, and identity in complex ways, showing Sam’s real
support system to lie outside of her family, in her friends and
colleagues. While the romance between Austin and Sam is central to the
plot, the real narrative is that of Sam standing up for what she wants
in life, and learning to love who she is. &lt;em&gt;A Cinderella Story&lt;/em&gt; is a spin
on a fairytale which prioritizes Sam’s story: her growth comes not from
falling in love with Austin, but from recognising what she wants and
fighting for it. Apart from Duff’s moving portrayal, we also get an
iconic rainy make-out scene at the end to a Jimmy Eat World song, so
what’s not to like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I think it’s clear that Hilary Duff is responsible for much of the magic of mid-2000s teen movies, and helped fortify a specific genre of film that, although dated, remains endlessly entertaining (and loveable) even now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fatima Jafar</name></author><category term="issue1" /><summary type="html">Hilary Duff has played a central role in my life since I was a child. All I wanted was to live in a small suburban town and wear bandannas and pom-pom scrunchies in my hair like her and Lalaine in Lizzie McGuire. When I think back to which mid-2000s celebrity's oeuvre I hold the most dear to my heart, the magical work of the Duff reigns supreme. Below, I share four of my favourite Duff films and the lasting impact they have had on me. Raise Your Voice We begin with the 2004 box-office bomb, Raise Your Voice. Full of cringe-inducing musical performances and first kisses, this film is the perfect introduction to the messy and hilarious genre of music-centered romance movies of the 2000s (High School Musical (2006) and Camp Rock (2008) being the obvious examples of when the genre perfected itself). Hilary Duff plays Terri Fletcher, a sixteen-year-old living in Flagstaff, Arizona, who dreams of becoming a singer. The film takes a dark turn when her brother Paul is killed in a car accident, after a Three Days Grace concert. Terri’s mother urges her to go to a music conservatory on the West Coast over the summer, to follow her heart and fulfil her late brother’s dreams for her. Once there, Terri tastes her first slice of reality outside of her small-town upbringing: mean girls, cute boys, and a competitive music school. What follows is a heartfelt story about family and first romance, replete with saccharine dialogue about ‘the transcendent power of music.’ The Lizzie McGuire Movie Usually the favourite of many Duff fans, The Lizzie McGuire Movie (2003) follows the characters of the titular television show as they embark on their graduation trip to Rome. What begins as an innocent school trip full of pizza and piazzas swiftly turns into a whirlwind journey for Lizzie, who is pursued by Italian pop star Paolo due to her uncanny likeness to his singing partner Isabella. Lizzie is roped into performing with him (and pretending to be Isabella) at the Italian Music Awards, throwing her into the glittering world of fame. As the story unfolds, however, we realise Paolo may not be exactly who we thought him to be. The movie is beautifully chaotic in its nonsensical storyline, overflowing with excitement, intrigue, and a phenomenal soundtrack which I still listen to. We also finally (finally!) have romance between Lizzie and Good Guy Gordo, and for that, I am eternally grateful. The Perfect Man In my opinion, The Perfect Man is one of the Duff films that unfortunately gets overshadowed by the rest, and is rarely lauded with the praise it deserves. Set in Brooklyn, the film follows the lives of single mother Jean (played brilliantly by Heather Locklear) and her two daughters, Holly and Zoe. Sick of seeing her mother heartbroken over another deadbeat man, Holly (Duff) decides to play matchmaker and set her mother up with a fake ‘secret admirer’ named Ben, based off of her friend’s restaurateur uncle (played by Chris Noth of Sex and the City fame). As Holly struggles to keep the secret of the matchmaking from her mother (with the help of artsy boy Adam played by Ben Feldman, who I concede is a big reason why I love this film so much), we see mother and daughter deal with the ups and downs of romantic life. The film pushes beyond its own fluttery romcom scope to become a testament to both family and womanhood. Soundtracked to some beautiful 2000s melodies (and containing possibly the happiest moment in cinematic history: all three women dancing to Kaci Battaglia’s “I Will Learn to Love Again” in a living-room routine), The Perfect Man is a perfect feel-good movie I find myself coming back to more often than I would care to admit. A Cinderella Story The last movie on my list is the 2004 cinematic triumph, A Cinderella Story. Set in a drought-ridden San Fernando Valley, Duff plays Sam Montgomery, a teenage girl who lives with her emotionally abusive stepmother and stepsisters and works at her late father’s diner after school. The story is, of course, that of Cinderella, just with a few more flip phones and low-rise jeans. As an escape from her tumultuous home life, she finds refuge in an online pen pal ‘Nomad’, who is secretly quarterback Austin Ames (played by none other than 2000s heartthrob Chad Michael Murray). They finally meet at the Halloween dance (where Austin is unable to recognise her because of a mask?) before Sam rushes to get back to the diner by midnight. She accidentally drops her cell phone while leaving the dance, thus prompting Austin to find the identity of his mystery girl. The film explores ideas of friendship, family, and identity in complex ways, showing Sam’s real support system to lie outside of her family, in her friends and colleagues. While the romance between Austin and Sam is central to the plot, the real narrative is that of Sam standing up for what she wants in life, and learning to love who she is. A Cinderella Story is a spin on a fairytale which prioritizes Sam’s story: her growth comes not from falling in love with Austin, but from recognising what she wants and fighting for it. Apart from Duff’s moving portrayal, we also get an iconic rainy make-out scene at the end to a Jimmy Eat World song, so what’s not to like? All in all, I think it’s clear that Hilary Duff is responsible for much of the magic of mid-2000s teen movies, and helped fortify a specific genre of film that, although dated, remains endlessly entertaining (and loveable) even now.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Acceptance, Loud Conversations, and Everything In-Between: ‘Sex Education’ Review</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/gabriele.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Acceptance, Loud Conversations, and Everything In-Between: 'Sex Education' Review" /><published>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/gabriele</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/gabriele.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sex Education&lt;/em&gt;, the buzzed-about Netflix series, recently released its
second season. For many, the show’s main draw is its humour. For me, it
was an exposure of human vulnerability. Sex and sexuality make us
vulnerable and &lt;em&gt;Sex Education&lt;/em&gt; perfectly captures that. While
incorporating romantic comedy tropes, the show strayed from its
‘perfect’ narrative and exposed sex beyond its romantic implications. It
unravelled multiplicities and withered from ‘universal’ flawless
romantic experiences, emphasising individual struggles, paths and
idiosyncrasies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The show helps to generate a healthy narrative and offers a breath of
fresh air in the deep-seated traditional perspectives around sex. Young
people and their sexual experiences sit at the heart of &lt;em&gt;Sex Education&lt;/em&gt;,
tackling everything from fetishes, first times, masturbation, sexual
traumas, abortion, and figuring out one’s body. In the midst of this,
the show tries to project the message that, when it comes to sex,
normativeness is not about similarity, but difference. Emphasises that
one should not try to follow or strive for their sex life to fit into
some normative paradigmatic narrative, it aims to embrace disparities
and encourage us to accept it by showing individual struggles and their
failures to conform to these traditional characteristics. It highlights
that nothing about sexual experience is ‘universal’, breaking the
fatigued stereotypical narrative generated by traditional romantic
comedies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sex Education&lt;/em&gt; also stresses that sex is a dangerous tool that can
cause significant harm. Even Otis’ mother, and sex therapist, says that
‘sex can ruin lives’ and should be handled responsibly. The main
character Aimee has clearly been a victim of irresponsible sexual
behaviour and the show follows her story of dealing with the
psychological trauma she experienced as a result, which made her
re-define and rethink her sexuality. Through personal stories, the
series shows that sex education should not just constitute putting a
condom on a banana, lessons should extend in teaching young people about
things like consent and sexual assault, after all, pregnancies and STI’s
are not the only consequences of sexual activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of this, &lt;em&gt;Sex Education&lt;/em&gt; effectively explores the notion of
masculinity, the hardship of accepting your own body, alienation, the
myth of a ‘normative’ sexual narrative, and coming to terms with one’s
sexual identity. It emphasises that sexuality is a journey; far from
anything static or universal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this assertion may feel obvious to some, &lt;em&gt;Sex Education&lt;/em&gt; clearly
visualises these complexities and puts them into perspective. It expands
traditional sexual narratives and teaches powerful lessons about a
subject that is already hard enough to navigate, while traditional sex
education and romantic comedies miss a myriad of important points.
Hopefully, the show’s success will inspire healthier sexual narratives,
louder and more comfortable conversations, while encouraging the
‘Netflix generation’ to ditch the stereotypes and accept that
normativeness lies in differences.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gabriele Sungailaite</name></author><category term="issue1" /><summary type="html">Sex Education, the buzzed-about Netflix series, recently released its second season. For many, the show’s main draw is its humour. For me, it was an exposure of human vulnerability. Sex and sexuality make us vulnerable and Sex Education perfectly captures that. While incorporating romantic comedy tropes, the show strayed from its ‘perfect’ narrative and exposed sex beyond its romantic implications. It unravelled multiplicities and withered from ‘universal’ flawless romantic experiences, emphasising individual struggles, paths and idiosyncrasies. The show helps to generate a healthy narrative and offers a breath of fresh air in the deep-seated traditional perspectives around sex. Young people and their sexual experiences sit at the heart of Sex Education, tackling everything from fetishes, first times, masturbation, sexual traumas, abortion, and figuring out one’s body. In the midst of this, the show tries to project the message that, when it comes to sex, normativeness is not about similarity, but difference. Emphasises that one should not try to follow or strive for their sex life to fit into some normative paradigmatic narrative, it aims to embrace disparities and encourage us to accept it by showing individual struggles and their failures to conform to these traditional characteristics. It highlights that nothing about sexual experience is ‘universal’, breaking the fatigued stereotypical narrative generated by traditional romantic comedies. Sex Education also stresses that sex is a dangerous tool that can cause significant harm. Even Otis’ mother, and sex therapist, says that ‘sex can ruin lives’ and should be handled responsibly. The main character Aimee has clearly been a victim of irresponsible sexual behaviour and the show follows her story of dealing with the psychological trauma she experienced as a result, which made her re-define and rethink her sexuality. Through personal stories, the series shows that sex education should not just constitute putting a condom on a banana, lessons should extend in teaching young people about things like consent and sexual assault, after all, pregnancies and STI’s are not the only consequences of sexual activity. On top of this, Sex Education effectively explores the notion of masculinity, the hardship of accepting your own body, alienation, the myth of a ‘normative’ sexual narrative, and coming to terms with one’s sexual identity. It emphasises that sexuality is a journey; far from anything static or universal. While this assertion may feel obvious to some, Sex Education clearly visualises these complexities and puts them into perspective. It expands traditional sexual narratives and teaches powerful lessons about a subject that is already hard enough to navigate, while traditional sex education and romantic comedies miss a myriad of important points. Hopefully, the show’s success will inspire healthier sexual narratives, louder and more comfortable conversations, while encouraging the ‘Netflix generation’ to ditch the stereotypes and accept that normativeness lies in differences.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sunrise in Vienna – an exploration of the city of Vienna in Richard Linklater’s Before Sunrise.</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/isabella.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sunrise in Vienna -- an exploration of the city of Vienna in Richard Linklater's Before Sunrise." /><published>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/isabella</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/isabella.html">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes cities can be as important to a film as the characters
themselves – to the point where, in some cases, the city becomes a
character in itself. This is the case in Before Sunrise, a film that
tells the story of the brief but profound meeting of Jesse and Celine,
who spend the night walking around the city of Vienna. The film centres
itself completely around the conversations of the couple, who slowly
(but also quickly – the story takes place over the course of about 12
hours) fall in love with one another. As a result, other characters –
the people they meet and interact with on the way: the arguing couple,
the amateur Viennese actors, the fortune-teller, the poet – only get a
few minutes on screen. I would argue that these minor characters are
parts of a large whole – they collectively become the character of the
city of Vienna, along with the actual physical location, which gains a
livelihood of its own over the course of the film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many shots throughout the film in which Celine and Jesse
slowly walk out of view, their conversation dimming out, and the
viewer’s eye is instead directed to other figures in the frame: the
people of Vienna. This brings to my mind the idea that Celine and
Jesse’s story is just one of the many stories that are taking place and
have taken place in that beautiful city as they walk through it. This is
a familiar feeling that I don’t quite know the name for, the feeling
that you are just one character in a never-ending, chronologically
ordered end credits sequence. I often get this feeling in train stations
or airport arrival areas, when I am sitting waiting for my train or
aeroplane, and observing the scenes of arguments, first meetings,
emotional reunions. Linklater captures this feeling very well in
focusing as much on the city of Vienna as he does on the relationship
between Jesse and Celine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sequence in the film that really strikes me every time I watch it is
near the end, where Linklater shows a series of shots of the locations
that Jesse and Celine “inhabited” (as the script phrases it) over the
course of the night, and are now being touched by the light of the early
morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of my own photos of Vienna (taken on 35mm in an attempt to
get closer to the idea of 1990’s Vienna like the Vienna from the film?)
set next to my descriptions of the ‘empty’ shots of Vienna from this
sequence in Before Sunrise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eye-level shot showing the green bridge that Celine and Jesse walked on
when they first got to Vienna; no one is discernible in the shot and the
only thing moving is a train passing by underneath: we see the whole
train pass by and then the shot lingers for a few seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(PHOTO)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zoomed out shot of the boat-restaurant Jesse and Celine ate at; the only
thing moving is the water of the river Danube passing by past the boat;
then close up shot of the table Jesse and Celine were sitting at, with a
bridge in the background, on which cars are driving by in the distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(PHOTO)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eye-level shot of the Albertina balcony, with the view of the Opera
House and Albertinaplatz; no one sitting on the balustrade (although the
presence of the young couple lingers); no other figures in the shot; a
couple of vans drive by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(PHOTO)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eye-level shot of the alleyway where Celine and Jesse sat to talk about
the differences between men and women; again, no one is in the shot but
the audience can definitely feel the presence of the couple sitting
there just a few hours before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(PHOTO)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eye-level shot of the graveyard that Celine and Jesse visited; no
figures in the shot except dozens of little white statuettes of Jesus
attached to the top of the graves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(PHOTO)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zoomed out, slightly high angle shot of the Kleines Cafe where Celine
had her hand read by a fortune-teller; now an old man with a yellow
shopping bag crosses the square alone – the theme of time passing is
picked up subtly here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(PHOTO)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distant shot of the park where Celine and Jesse sat down in the middle
of the night to have wine and stay there until dawn; it looks different
in the morning light – you can see the buildings in the distance;
there’s an old lady walking across the shot (again a nod to the theme of
time), and she passes a spot on the grass where there seems to be the
remains of a wine bottle and glasses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(PHOTO&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Isabella Jakobsen</name></author><category term="issue1" /><summary type="html">Sometimes cities can be as important to a film as the characters themselves – to the point where, in some cases, the city becomes a character in itself. This is the case in Before Sunrise, a film that tells the story of the brief but profound meeting of Jesse and Celine, who spend the night walking around the city of Vienna. The film centres itself completely around the conversations of the couple, who slowly (but also quickly – the story takes place over the course of about 12 hours) fall in love with one another. As a result, other characters – the people they meet and interact with on the way: the arguing couple, the amateur Viennese actors, the fortune-teller, the poet – only get a few minutes on screen. I would argue that these minor characters are parts of a large whole – they collectively become the character of the city of Vienna, along with the actual physical location, which gains a livelihood of its own over the course of the film. There are many shots throughout the film in which Celine and Jesse slowly walk out of view, their conversation dimming out, and the viewer’s eye is instead directed to other figures in the frame: the people of Vienna. This brings to my mind the idea that Celine and Jesse’s story is just one of the many stories that are taking place and have taken place in that beautiful city as they walk through it. This is a familiar feeling that I don’t quite know the name for, the feeling that you are just one character in a never-ending, chronologically ordered end credits sequence. I often get this feeling in train stations or airport arrival areas, when I am sitting waiting for my train or aeroplane, and observing the scenes of arguments, first meetings, emotional reunions. Linklater captures this feeling very well in focusing as much on the city of Vienna as he does on the relationship between Jesse and Celine. The sequence in the film that really strikes me every time I watch it is near the end, where Linklater shows a series of shots of the locations that Jesse and Celine “inhabited” (as the script phrases it) over the course of the night, and are now being touched by the light of the early morning. Here are some of my own photos of Vienna (taken on 35mm in an attempt to get closer to the idea of 1990’s Vienna like the Vienna from the film?) set next to my descriptions of the ‘empty’ shots of Vienna from this sequence in Before Sunrise: Eye-level shot showing the green bridge that Celine and Jesse walked on when they first got to Vienna; no one is discernible in the shot and the only thing moving is a train passing by underneath: we see the whole train pass by and then the shot lingers for a few seconds. (PHOTO) Zoomed out shot of the boat-restaurant Jesse and Celine ate at; the only thing moving is the water of the river Danube passing by past the boat; then close up shot of the table Jesse and Celine were sitting at, with a bridge in the background, on which cars are driving by in the distance. (PHOTO) Eye-level shot of the Albertina balcony, with the view of the Opera House and Albertinaplatz; no one sitting on the balustrade (although the presence of the young couple lingers); no other figures in the shot; a couple of vans drive by. (PHOTO) Eye-level shot of the alleyway where Celine and Jesse sat to talk about the differences between men and women; again, no one is in the shot but the audience can definitely feel the presence of the couple sitting there just a few hours before. (PHOTO) Eye-level shot of the graveyard that Celine and Jesse visited; no figures in the shot except dozens of little white statuettes of Jesus attached to the top of the graves. (PHOTO) Zoomed out, slightly high angle shot of the Kleines Cafe where Celine had her hand read by a fortune-teller; now an old man with a yellow shopping bag crosses the square alone – the theme of time passing is picked up subtly here. (PHOTO) Distant shot of the park where Celine and Jesse sat down in the middle of the night to have wine and stay there until dawn; it looks different in the morning light – you can see the buildings in the distance; there’s an old lady walking across the shot (again a nod to the theme of time), and she passes a spot on the grass where there seems to be the remains of a wine bottle and glasses. (PHOTO</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Era of Climate Change Cinema</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/kirese.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Era of Climate Change Cinema" /><published>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/kirese</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/kirese.html">&lt;p&gt;At first glance, climate change does not seem as relevant to cinema as
the themes of love, war, and even horror. Is it possible to insert
climate change as a theme, or even a genre, into cinema as we know it?
This “cinema as we know it” is, by its nature, fluid. Cinema demands
change and change is a facet (and asset) of cinema. With this in mind,
we must ask whether climate change as depicted in films suggests that
cinema is entering into a new era. Maybe it’s apt to reflect on whether
we see science-fiction as a medium that both reflects our anxieties and
protects us from the bleak reality that may be closer than we think.
It’s not for now, in our present states of mind, what “will be” but what
“&lt;em&gt;may be”&lt;/em&gt;, and the movies show exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cinema is fickle. Westerns, once popular with mid-twentieth century
audiences, are hardly made or even taken notice of in our present time.
So too has the musical suffered after its boom in the latter century,
and the silent film is, of course, also invisible. Action films are
entertaining “roller-coaster rides” that attract billions of dollars,
but how long will that last? Films are moments in time, transitory
glances at what is, once was, and what will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Climate change, on the other hand, is a different beast. It’s not hard
to notice that climate-change cinema is deeply rooted in science-fiction
films. &lt;em&gt;Blade Runner&lt;/em&gt; (1982) with its nightmarish, post-modern Los
Angeles of 2019 is a frenzy of violent energy, depicting industrial
pollution that goes hand in hand with human advancements in machinery
and architecture. It’s not surprising that the director, Ridley Scott,
was inspired by Fritz Lang’s &lt;em&gt;Metropolis&lt;/em&gt; (1927). I wonder, then, if
this was the starting point of “climate change cinema”? &lt;em&gt;Metropolis’&lt;/em&gt;
“big city” spectacles of skyscrapers, capitalistic incongruities between
workers and enterprise owners highlighted the inequalities of its time,
but also inadvertently created a domino effect, whereby science-fiction
films like &lt;em&gt;Blade Runner,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Day after Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Avatar&lt;/em&gt; reflect
the same preoccupations about industrial-based destruction of humanity
and its environment. Just as &lt;em&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/em&gt; reflects near-future events,
so too does science-fiction shapeshift into representations of the
growing potentiality for climate catastrophes. Pessimism bursts through
films of our present day: doom and gloom are inevitable circumstances in
films like Bong Joon-ho’s &lt;em&gt;Snowpiercer&lt;/em&gt; (2013)&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; in which efforts to
resolve global warming backfire and lead to social crises; Alfonso
Cuarón’s &lt;em&gt;Children of Men&lt;/em&gt; relies on ambiguous tension, positing
infertility as an apocalyptic crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are all films of speculation. Whether or not there are films
nowadays that truly depict the &lt;em&gt;present&lt;/em&gt; is questionable. At least, none
come to mind. Undoubtedly, like in the films mentioned above, climate
change is the causal element of the social issues of the dystopian
realities. Notably, these fictional stories always portray the
after-effects of devastation, instead of a world &lt;em&gt;becoming&lt;/em&gt; devastated,
which is the world of today. For instance, In &lt;em&gt;Avatar,&lt;/em&gt; in an era of
post-devastation, humans resort to the colonization of other planets for
resources, whereas in &lt;em&gt;Blade Runner,&lt;/em&gt; the effects of climate change are
reflected in its Los Angeles mise-en-scène that exudes the paradoxical
blend of the aesthetically pleasing, colorful lighting and the noxious
pollution and decay that swarms the city, as a protective shield. Like
the characters of &lt;em&gt;Blade Runner,&lt;/em&gt; we, too, are surrounded by a layering
shield and protected from reality. The cinema is our protective cover
and blindfold. Climate change is represented as more of a looming shadow
in fictional cinema. It’s essentially a type of boogeyman that we must
fear, but, as it turns out, we never believe that it is actually real.
The catastrophic events of &lt;em&gt;The Day After Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt; or the “boogeyman”
technological dangers of &lt;em&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/em&gt; are frankly entertaining- not to
be taken too seriously. There is little power in expounding on the
hypothetical, especially when it is so distractingly beautiful, as in
&lt;em&gt;Blade Runner&lt;/em&gt;, or any of those shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Significantly, however, these films do not blame anyone but humanity
itself as the central causal destructive force that propels its own
environment into complete decimation. It’s explicit in films like
&lt;em&gt;Annihilation&lt;/em&gt; (2018)&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; which uses cancer to symbolize the tumorous,
malignant and instinctive power of humans to self-annihilate. Even
&lt;em&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/em&gt; references the silver lining of humanity’s
destruction. In one scene, Captain America takes note that he sees more
animal life in the Hudson River, as if to suggest that our destruction
implicitly corresponds to the creation and preservation of other species
on our planet.It is not an outside, extra-terrestrial event that
threatens the balance of human power; it’s us. The cinema of science
fiction thus seems to be pigeon-holed in futuristic reality. Granted, it
is what it has always represented. However, given the surge of recent
climate phenomena, film must open its boundaries and defy genre. Climate
change should not be confined to science fiction, nor should it be
trapped within the temporality of the near-future or the hypothetical.
As &lt;em&gt;Annihilation&lt;/em&gt; suggests, in order to create a new world, we must
efface the old; to create a new cinema of climate change, we must
destroy the rigidity of generic boundaries that categorize climate
change phenomena in the bracket of science-fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Documentaries may be a more fruitful approach at analyzing the potential
for “climate change cinema” (however we define that ). &lt;em&gt;Planet Earth&lt;/em&gt;
and &lt;em&gt;Our Planet&lt;/em&gt; provide the most piercing and insightful glimpses into
planetary devastation. They’re hard to watch,tearing down beauty in
frightful images of negation. Shows such as these make us interrogate
the present as a growing devastation of our surroundings, a darkness
slowly covering the entire earth. Whether there is transformative power
in such an approach of demonstrating horrific, non-fictional events is
debatable. The filmic reality is nonetheless a heightened reality and
subconsciously, we believe that the on-screen illusions bear little
resemblance to the outside world. Documentaries are meant to break
through illusion and create stories from this intrusion into an “other”
reality or world that is seemingly inaccessible to the average human.
Therefore they ostensibly portray “what is” and consequently, “will be.”
&lt;em&gt;Planet Earth&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Our Planet&lt;/em&gt; are made to be “intrusions” or a
veritable 21^st^ century Brechtian V-effect, a startling shock that’s
meant to reverberate down the spine and stimulate action. It’s puzzling
that we are so affected by real images in the fleeting moments of
watching a film. It’s even more puzzling that the V-effect has been
crippled into only reaching the first stage of shock, with reflection
and action are substituted by indolence and inaction. It begs the
question whether images of catastrophe are rendered so banal that we can
no longer be affected by them, and whether we are so trapped in
artificiality and hypothesis that we can no longer recognize illusion
from reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within cinema lies the speculation of whether there can be a “right”
approach to portraying a climate crisis. Can pessimism be effective, or
would it be more useful to promote films which end on a note of renewal,
such as &lt;em&gt;Interstellar&lt;/em&gt;? Or, it may be too late. Admittedly, this article
verges on pessimism and can be accused of being as speculative as the
films it critiques. However, I do not want to be pessimistic and nor do
I wish to reflect the gloom and doom of science-fiction films.
Speculation, however, is inevitable. The times are changing, and cinema,
as always, will change with it – that is, if it finally reneges
speculation in favor of a veritable depiction of what is happening in
front of our faces.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kirese</name></author><category term="issue1" /><summary type="html">At first glance, climate change does not seem as relevant to cinema as the themes of love, war, and even horror. Is it possible to insert climate change as a theme, or even a genre, into cinema as we know it? This “cinema as we know it” is, by its nature, fluid. Cinema demands change and change is a facet (and asset) of cinema. With this in mind, we must ask whether climate change as depicted in films suggests that cinema is entering into a new era. Maybe it’s apt to reflect on whether we see science-fiction as a medium that both reflects our anxieties and protects us from the bleak reality that may be closer than we think. It’s not for now, in our present states of mind, what “will be” but what “may be”, and the movies show exactly that. Cinema is fickle. Westerns, once popular with mid-twentieth century audiences, are hardly made or even taken notice of in our present time. So too has the musical suffered after its boom in the latter century, and the silent film is, of course, also invisible. Action films are entertaining “roller-coaster rides” that attract billions of dollars, but how long will that last? Films are moments in time, transitory glances at what is, once was, and what will be. Climate change, on the other hand, is a different beast. It’s not hard to notice that climate-change cinema is deeply rooted in science-fiction films. Blade Runner (1982) with its nightmarish, post-modern Los Angeles of 2019 is a frenzy of violent energy, depicting industrial pollution that goes hand in hand with human advancements in machinery and architecture. It’s not surprising that the director, Ridley Scott, was inspired by Fritz Lang’s Metropolis (1927). I wonder, then, if this was the starting point of “climate change cinema”? Metropolis’ “big city” spectacles of skyscrapers, capitalistic incongruities between workers and enterprise owners highlighted the inequalities of its time, but also inadvertently created a domino effect, whereby science-fiction films like Blade Runner, The Day after Tomorrow and Avatar reflect the same preoccupations about industrial-based destruction of humanity and its environment. Just as Black Mirror reflects near-future events, so too does science-fiction shapeshift into representations of the growing potentiality for climate catastrophes. Pessimism bursts through films of our present day: doom and gloom are inevitable circumstances in films like Bong Joon-ho’s Snowpiercer (2013), in which efforts to resolve global warming backfire and lead to social crises; Alfonso Cuarón’s Children of Men relies on ambiguous tension, positing infertility as an apocalyptic crisis. These are all films of speculation. Whether or not there are films nowadays that truly depict the present is questionable. At least, none come to mind. Undoubtedly, like in the films mentioned above, climate change is the causal element of the social issues of the dystopian realities. Notably, these fictional stories always portray the after-effects of devastation, instead of a world becoming devastated, which is the world of today. For instance, In Avatar, in an era of post-devastation, humans resort to the colonization of other planets for resources, whereas in Blade Runner, the effects of climate change are reflected in its Los Angeles mise-en-scène that exudes the paradoxical blend of the aesthetically pleasing, colorful lighting and the noxious pollution and decay that swarms the city, as a protective shield. Like the characters of Blade Runner, we, too, are surrounded by a layering shield and protected from reality. The cinema is our protective cover and blindfold. Climate change is represented as more of a looming shadow in fictional cinema. It’s essentially a type of boogeyman that we must fear, but, as it turns out, we never believe that it is actually real. The catastrophic events of The Day After Tomorrow or the “boogeyman” technological dangers of Black Mirror are frankly entertaining- not to be taken too seriously. There is little power in expounding on the hypothetical, especially when it is so distractingly beautiful, as in Blade Runner, or any of those shows. Significantly, however, these films do not blame anyone but humanity itself as the central causal destructive force that propels its own environment into complete decimation. It’s explicit in films like Annihilation (2018), which uses cancer to symbolize the tumorous, malignant and instinctive power of humans to self-annihilate. Even Avengers: Endgame references the silver lining of humanity’s destruction. In one scene, Captain America takes note that he sees more animal life in the Hudson River, as if to suggest that our destruction implicitly corresponds to the creation and preservation of other species on our planet.It is not an outside, extra-terrestrial event that threatens the balance of human power; it’s us. The cinema of science fiction thus seems to be pigeon-holed in futuristic reality. Granted, it is what it has always represented. However, given the surge of recent climate phenomena, film must open its boundaries and defy genre. Climate change should not be confined to science fiction, nor should it be trapped within the temporality of the near-future or the hypothetical. As Annihilation suggests, in order to create a new world, we must efface the old; to create a new cinema of climate change, we must destroy the rigidity of generic boundaries that categorize climate change phenomena in the bracket of science-fiction. Documentaries may be a more fruitful approach at analyzing the potential for “climate change cinema” (however we define that ). Planet Earth and Our Planet provide the most piercing and insightful glimpses into planetary devastation. They’re hard to watch,tearing down beauty in frightful images of negation. Shows such as these make us interrogate the present as a growing devastation of our surroundings, a darkness slowly covering the entire earth. Whether there is transformative power in such an approach of demonstrating horrific, non-fictional events is debatable. The filmic reality is nonetheless a heightened reality and subconsciously, we believe that the on-screen illusions bear little resemblance to the outside world. Documentaries are meant to break through illusion and create stories from this intrusion into an “other” reality or world that is seemingly inaccessible to the average human. Therefore they ostensibly portray “what is” and consequently, “will be.” Planet Earth and Our Planet are made to be “intrusions” or a veritable 21^st^ century Brechtian V-effect, a startling shock that’s meant to reverberate down the spine and stimulate action. It’s puzzling that we are so affected by real images in the fleeting moments of watching a film. It’s even more puzzling that the V-effect has been crippled into only reaching the first stage of shock, with reflection and action are substituted by indolence and inaction. It begs the question whether images of catastrophe are rendered so banal that we can no longer be affected by them, and whether we are so trapped in artificiality and hypothesis that we can no longer recognize illusion from reality. Within cinema lies the speculation of whether there can be a “right” approach to portraying a climate crisis. Can pessimism be effective, or would it be more useful to promote films which end on a note of renewal, such as Interstellar? Or, it may be too late. Admittedly, this article verges on pessimism and can be accused of being as speculative as the films it critiques. However, I do not want to be pessimistic and nor do I wish to reflect the gloom and doom of science-fiction films. Speculation, however, is inevitable. The times are changing, and cinema, as always, will change with it – that is, if it finally reneges speculation in favor of a veritable depiction of what is happening in front of our faces.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Uncut Gems’ Review</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/noah.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Uncut Gems' Review" /><published>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/noah</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/noah.html">&lt;p&gt;Uncut Gems, the Safdie brothers’ latest film, is a love letter to
Manhattan’s Diamond District and the shysters who run it. It’s a homage
to cheaters who make a lot of money and try desperately to juggle their
vices with their families. Fittingly, the film stars Adam Sandler as
Howard Ratner, a jewellery store owner up to his neck in shady business
deals and lies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film moves fast. The only constant the audience has to hold on to is
their morally dubious protagonist, who remains in motion. One minute
he’s making high money bets on basketball games, the next he’s sitting
alongside his teenage son at Passover Seder. He’s sleazy and a bit
pathetic, but we can’t help rooting for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Howard owes money to his loan-shark brother-in-law Arno (Eric Bogosian),
who is convoyed by a pair of seemingly harmless thugs. Howard’s plan for
reimbursement is an African black opal stone that he intends to sell at
auction for $300,000. Instead, pro basketball player Kevin Garnett -
played by himself in a breakout role - has a spiritual connection with
the stone and borrows it. Garnett loans him his Celtic championship ring
as collateral for the “priceless” stone, which Howard pawns in order to
make a big bet on the Celtics game. The rest of the film untangles like
a high stakes roulette game; you don’t know what’s going to happen, but
you do know that if the Celtics don’t win the game, things aren't going
to end well for Howard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uncut Gems is not easy to watch, so if you’re prone to anxiety - proceed
with caution. Alongside the bet, Howard is trying to salvage his
marriage with soon to be ex-wife (Idina Menzel) and focuses all his
sexual frustration toward his mistress (Julia Fox.). In one particularly
bizarre but memorable scene, Howard suspects his mistress of canoodling
with The Weeknd at a club (yes, that The Weeknd), and attacks him before
storming off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sandler is beyond good in a role that feels out of character when
compared to his previous work in films like Happy Gilmore and Billy
Madison. Howard is a crook, yes, but we like him because he’s an
unabashed optimist, a go-getter, a hard worker who never gives up on his
dream to make a shit ton of cash. The Safdie brothers never criticize
him because of his flaws, and we don’t either. Instead, the film makes
us sympathize with the realities of life, in which there are no heroes
or villains. Like the uncut gems that Howard obsesses over, this film is
rough, but also a piece of sheer beauty. If you don’t mind two-hour
anxiety attacks and a lot of New York accents screaming over each other,
&lt;em&gt;Uncut Gems&lt;/em&gt; is definitely worth watching.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Noah Eckstein</name></author><category term="issue1" /><summary type="html">Uncut Gems, the Safdie brothers’ latest film, is a love letter to Manhattan’s Diamond District and the shysters who run it. It’s a homage to cheaters who make a lot of money and try desperately to juggle their vices with their families. Fittingly, the film stars Adam Sandler as Howard Ratner, a jewellery store owner up to his neck in shady business deals and lies. The film moves fast. The only constant the audience has to hold on to is their morally dubious protagonist, who remains in motion. One minute he’s making high money bets on basketball games, the next he’s sitting alongside his teenage son at Passover Seder. He’s sleazy and a bit pathetic, but we can’t help rooting for him. Howard owes money to his loan-shark brother-in-law Arno (Eric Bogosian), who is convoyed by a pair of seemingly harmless thugs. Howard’s plan for reimbursement is an African black opal stone that he intends to sell at auction for $300,000. Instead, pro basketball player Kevin Garnett - played by himself in a breakout role - has a spiritual connection with the stone and borrows it. Garnett loans him his Celtic championship ring as collateral for the “priceless” stone, which Howard pawns in order to make a big bet on the Celtics game. The rest of the film untangles like a high stakes roulette game; you don’t know what’s going to happen, but you do know that if the Celtics don’t win the game, things aren't going to end well for Howard. Uncut Gems is not easy to watch, so if you’re prone to anxiety - proceed with caution. Alongside the bet, Howard is trying to salvage his marriage with soon to be ex-wife (Idina Menzel) and focuses all his sexual frustration toward his mistress (Julia Fox.). In one particularly bizarre but memorable scene, Howard suspects his mistress of canoodling with The Weeknd at a club (yes, that The Weeknd), and attacks him before storming off. Sandler is beyond good in a role that feels out of character when compared to his previous work in films like Happy Gilmore and Billy Madison. Howard is a crook, yes, but we like him because he’s an unabashed optimist, a go-getter, a hard worker who never gives up on his dream to make a shit ton of cash. The Safdie brothers never criticize him because of his flaws, and we don’t either. Instead, the film makes us sympathize with the realities of life, in which there are no heroes or villains. Like the uncut gems that Howard obsesses over, this film is rough, but also a piece of sheer beauty. If you don’t mind two-hour anxiety attacks and a lot of New York accents screaming over each other, Uncut Gems is definitely worth watching.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">No Winners, Only Losers: ‘Parasite’ Review</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/sang.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No Winners, Only Losers: 'Parasite' Review" /><published>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/sang</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/sang.html">&lt;p&gt;It would be easy to label Bong Joon Ho’s &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt; as just a mere
critique of today’s society which enables and perpetuates an
unprecedented level of inequality. After all, inequality and social
mobility – or lack thereof – are issues that do not discriminate based
on nationality. Poverty and wealth coexist outside the tube stations of
London’s upscale neighbourhoods and at the street food stands of Seoul
operated by downtrodden Koreans and enjoyed by a crowd blissfully
oblivious to their struggles. Perhaps, it is the prevalence and severity
of such issues portrayed in &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt; that have helped the film reach a
truly global audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are introduced to the Kims in the opening scene of the film. Living
in a squalid semi-basement apartment in Seoul, the family lacks access
to the internet despite living in a country that boasts the world’s
fastest average internet speed. Their home is often urinated on from
above by drunkards, who see the Kims’ house as nothing more than a
urinal in the concrete jungle of Seoul. However, with deception and
luck, Ki-woo, the Kim family son, followed by the rest of the Kims,
infiltrate the home of the wealthy Park family, through various roles.
Ki-woo serves as the English teacher to Da-hye, the Park family
daughter, while Ki-Taek, the Kim family patriarch (albeit only in
title), serves as the Park family driver and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Ki-woo’s first visit to the Parks’ gated house on top of a hill, he
walks in and looks up in awe at the modern house designed by a renowned
Korean architect. Unbeknownst to him, the woman who greets him at the
door is not Da-hye’s mother but the live-in maid, Moon-gwang, a
privilege unimaginable to the Kims. What ensues is as Bong describes, “a
comedy without clowns, a tragedy without villains.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rich bashing is a trope that has been explored by numerous films before
&lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt;, and most likely will continue. However, &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt; is
different. Through the interactions between the Parks and the Kims,
Parasite shows us that its characters, despite their polar opposite
backgrounds, possess numerous indistinguishable traits. The rich and the
poor are both shockingly honest with their ulterior motives. The conmen
and their victims are both equally willing to employ deception, violence
and any other means necessary to meet their ends. Ultimately, the
cultured and the uncultured are both united by their lack of principles
and willingness to cross the lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bong and co-writer Han Jin-won present the whole truth of each character
– the good and the bad – and force us to question whether the actions
of each party are justified and choose where our sympathies lie. Poverty
is not the holy water that absolves the sins of deceit and violence,
neither is culture a justification for discrimination against those who
lack culture. Thus, it complicates our loyalties. Once again, &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt;
invokes our moral calculus by not only pitting the wealthy and the poor
against each other, but also by its depiction of hostilities between
those who come from the same socioeconomic background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty of &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt; is that in order for our judgements of the
characters to be impartial and fair, we are forced to rely on the
context and periphery details that Bong provides. Both the Kims and the
maid’s family were diligent – albeit failed – owners of King Castella
shop, a fast-food chain, which in Korea harks back to the 1998 IMF
crisis and symbolises the last stop on the journey to complete financial
ruin. From a briefly flashed medal, we glean that Chung-sook, the
matriarch of the Kim family, was once a successful athlete. From the
fatherly love that Dong-ik, the patriarch of the wealthy Park family,
shows towards his son, we understand that he is not like the
stereotypical ruthless millionaire. In fact, the flaws of &lt;em&gt;Parasite’s&lt;/em&gt;
loving, talented main characters are only put on display when their
livelihoods are threatened by others. Put shortly, their flaws stem from
today’s brutal Darwinian society that rewards the heartless and
subjugates the compassionate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it may be the case that the prevalence of issues such as social
inequality and lack of social mobility propelled &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt; to
international acclaim, the film shows us how easy is it is for a person&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;regardless of their background - to give in to the temptations of
greed, and the price we pay as a society for our indifference towards
each other’s suffering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Sang Park</name></author><category term="issue1" /><summary type="html">It would be easy to label Bong Joon Ho’s Parasite as just a mere critique of today’s society which enables and perpetuates an unprecedented level of inequality. After all, inequality and social mobility – or lack thereof – are issues that do not discriminate based on nationality. Poverty and wealth coexist outside the tube stations of London’s upscale neighbourhoods and at the street food stands of Seoul operated by downtrodden Koreans and enjoyed by a crowd blissfully oblivious to their struggles. Perhaps, it is the prevalence and severity of such issues portrayed in Parasite that have helped the film reach a truly global audience. We are introduced to the Kims in the opening scene of the film. Living in a squalid semi-basement apartment in Seoul, the family lacks access to the internet despite living in a country that boasts the world’s fastest average internet speed. Their home is often urinated on from above by drunkards, who see the Kims’ house as nothing more than a urinal in the concrete jungle of Seoul. However, with deception and luck, Ki-woo, the Kim family son, followed by the rest of the Kims, infiltrate the home of the wealthy Park family, through various roles. Ki-woo serves as the English teacher to Da-hye, the Park family daughter, while Ki-Taek, the Kim family patriarch (albeit only in title), serves as the Park family driver and so on. In Ki-woo’s first visit to the Parks’ gated house on top of a hill, he walks in and looks up in awe at the modern house designed by a renowned Korean architect. Unbeknownst to him, the woman who greets him at the door is not Da-hye’s mother but the live-in maid, Moon-gwang, a privilege unimaginable to the Kims. What ensues is as Bong describes, “a comedy without clowns, a tragedy without villains.” Rich bashing is a trope that has been explored by numerous films before Parasite, and most likely will continue. However, Parasite is different. Through the interactions between the Parks and the Kims, Parasite shows us that its characters, despite their polar opposite backgrounds, possess numerous indistinguishable traits. The rich and the poor are both shockingly honest with their ulterior motives. The conmen and their victims are both equally willing to employ deception, violence and any other means necessary to meet their ends. Ultimately, the cultured and the uncultured are both united by their lack of principles and willingness to cross the lines. Bong and co-writer Han Jin-won present the whole truth of each character – the good and the bad – and force us to question whether the actions of each party are justified and choose where our sympathies lie. Poverty is not the holy water that absolves the sins of deceit and violence, neither is culture a justification for discrimination against those who lack culture. Thus, it complicates our loyalties. Once again, Parasite invokes our moral calculus by not only pitting the wealthy and the poor against each other, but also by its depiction of hostilities between those who come from the same socioeconomic background. The beauty of Parasite is that in order for our judgements of the characters to be impartial and fair, we are forced to rely on the context and periphery details that Bong provides. Both the Kims and the maid’s family were diligent – albeit failed – owners of King Castella shop, a fast-food chain, which in Korea harks back to the 1998 IMF crisis and symbolises the last stop on the journey to complete financial ruin. From a briefly flashed medal, we glean that Chung-sook, the matriarch of the Kim family, was once a successful athlete. From the fatherly love that Dong-ik, the patriarch of the wealthy Park family, shows towards his son, we understand that he is not like the stereotypical ruthless millionaire. In fact, the flaws of Parasite’s loving, talented main characters are only put on display when their livelihoods are threatened by others. Put shortly, their flaws stem from today’s brutal Darwinian society that rewards the heartless and subjugates the compassionate. While it may be the case that the prevalence of issues such as social inequality and lack of social mobility propelled Parasite to international acclaim, the film shows us how easy is it is for a person regardless of their background - to give in to the temptations of greed, and the price we pay as a society for our indifference towards each other’s suffering.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An Elephant Sitting Still – dir. Hu Bo – 2018</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/sean.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Elephant Sitting Still -- dir. Hu Bo -- 2018" /><published>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/sean</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/sean.html">&lt;p&gt;The first shots of Hu Bo’s mammoth &lt;em&gt;An Elephant Sitting Still (2018)&lt;/em&gt;
begin with the central characters’ first waking moments of the day. Each
of them sit up, in silence, as we see them slip into a mood of quiet
melancholy which envelops them until the film ends. This quiet is
shattered in Bu’s flat, his drunken father shouting for his mother to
close the window to their cold high-rise flat, for the outside air is
carrying a foul smell. This is the world that Hu Bo’s film exists in;
where windows must be kept shut to keep out the stench of the city but
can’t keep out the depressive grey light; where the world exists only in
the immediate vicinity of the characters, the background rendered in
blur as if in a dream. There are no expansive, beautiful landscape shots
in this film, Hu Bo’s cinematography rendering the details of setting
irrelevant with an oppressively shallow depth of field that focuses
sharply on faces but nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film follows four loosely related central characters over the course
of one day, their stories slowly converging as evening draws in. Yu
Cheng is an adulterous gangster, who first mentions the titular elephant
in the waking moments of the film. The elephant sits in a zoo in
Manzhouli – a provincial city in Inner Mongolia on the border with
Russia – where it bares all insults and attempts to move it with a
commanding and unaffected resolve. It’s a romantic image, eventually
seducing each of the characters to embark on a pilgrimage to see it. Yu
Cheng’s younger brother is the bully at a failing high school, where he
is pushed down a flight of stairs by Wei Bu who must then flee. One of
Bu’s classmates and crush, Ling, is in a dispassionate affair with the
married vice-dean and is betrayed by her class-mates sharing a video of
them together on social media. She too must flee. The final and oldest
central character is Wang, a retiree forced out of the flat he owns and
shares with his son, daughter-in-law, and beloved granddaughter. The
four central characters’ paths weave in and out of each other across the
course of this day, each drawn more and more to the powerful stoicism of
the mythical Manzhouli elephant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was director Hu’s first and last film. He took his own life at the
age of 29, shortly after the film wrapped. While this film must be
viewed with this knowledge, to view it simply as a record of the
director’s suffering or as some kind of note would be wrong. Ultimately,
this interplay between the hope-filled pilgrimage towards Manzhouli and
the stiflingly melancholic mood of Hu’s cinematography evades this
characterisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In their interweaving storylines, each of the characters drifts through
the city in long unbroken shots, followed by Hu’s Steadicam. The shallow
depth of field removes all background detail, their apathy felt through
our inability to make out their surroundings and the expressions of
those that they interact with. Other characters are mere blurs, their
emotions and motivations clouded from view, but their voices
disconcertedly piercing, aggressive and without compassion. Despite
powerful attempts, the central characters are frequently misheard or
misunderstood. In combination, these choices affect an overwhelming
feeling of dream-like alienation, compounded with the growing sense that
we are never quite sure of what we hear. Non-sequiturs and stark,
unexplained noises burst out at us; intermittent crackling explosions,
presumably firecrackers for Chinese New Year, are always heard but never
seen; the blur of a schoolboy in a corridor is unresponsive but to blurt
“the world is a wasteland” before vanishing, in perhaps a projection of
Bu’s intrusive thoughts. In the film’s only still shot, while the
characters play shuttlecock in the headlights of a coach, the sound of
an elephant’s call pierces the silence in a haunting moment of
fantastical realism. Hu Bo’s cinematography of imprecision allows for
these moments of uncertainty, leaving viewers with the uneasy feeling
that perhaps you cannot trust your thoughts or your senses. Whether we
hear that haunting cry as one of defiance, futility, or madness, this
devastating film of Hu Bo is a cry that cannot be unheard.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sean Warmington</name></author><category term="issue1" /><summary type="html">The first shots of Hu Bo’s mammoth An Elephant Sitting Still (2018) begin with the central characters’ first waking moments of the day. Each of them sit up, in silence, as we see them slip into a mood of quiet melancholy which envelops them until the film ends. This quiet is shattered in Bu’s flat, his drunken father shouting for his mother to close the window to their cold high-rise flat, for the outside air is carrying a foul smell. This is the world that Hu Bo’s film exists in; where windows must be kept shut to keep out the stench of the city but can’t keep out the depressive grey light; where the world exists only in the immediate vicinity of the characters, the background rendered in blur as if in a dream. There are no expansive, beautiful landscape shots in this film, Hu Bo’s cinematography rendering the details of setting irrelevant with an oppressively shallow depth of field that focuses sharply on faces but nothing else. The film follows four loosely related central characters over the course of one day, their stories slowly converging as evening draws in. Yu Cheng is an adulterous gangster, who first mentions the titular elephant in the waking moments of the film. The elephant sits in a zoo in Manzhouli – a provincial city in Inner Mongolia on the border with Russia – where it bares all insults and attempts to move it with a commanding and unaffected resolve. It’s a romantic image, eventually seducing each of the characters to embark on a pilgrimage to see it. Yu Cheng’s younger brother is the bully at a failing high school, where he is pushed down a flight of stairs by Wei Bu who must then flee. One of Bu’s classmates and crush, Ling, is in a dispassionate affair with the married vice-dean and is betrayed by her class-mates sharing a video of them together on social media. She too must flee. The final and oldest central character is Wang, a retiree forced out of the flat he owns and shares with his son, daughter-in-law, and beloved granddaughter. The four central characters’ paths weave in and out of each other across the course of this day, each drawn more and more to the powerful stoicism of the mythical Manzhouli elephant. This was director Hu’s first and last film. He took his own life at the age of 29, shortly after the film wrapped. While this film must be viewed with this knowledge, to view it simply as a record of the director’s suffering or as some kind of note would be wrong. Ultimately, this interplay between the hope-filled pilgrimage towards Manzhouli and the stiflingly melancholic mood of Hu’s cinematography evades this characterisation. In their interweaving storylines, each of the characters drifts through the city in long unbroken shots, followed by Hu’s Steadicam. The shallow depth of field removes all background detail, their apathy felt through our inability to make out their surroundings and the expressions of those that they interact with. Other characters are mere blurs, their emotions and motivations clouded from view, but their voices disconcertedly piercing, aggressive and without compassion. Despite powerful attempts, the central characters are frequently misheard or misunderstood. In combination, these choices affect an overwhelming feeling of dream-like alienation, compounded with the growing sense that we are never quite sure of what we hear. Non-sequiturs and stark, unexplained noises burst out at us; intermittent crackling explosions, presumably firecrackers for Chinese New Year, are always heard but never seen; the blur of a schoolboy in a corridor is unresponsive but to blurt “the world is a wasteland” before vanishing, in perhaps a projection of Bu’s intrusive thoughts. In the film’s only still shot, while the characters play shuttlecock in the headlights of a coach, the sound of an elephant’s call pierces the silence in a haunting moment of fantastical realism. Hu Bo’s cinematography of imprecision allows for these moments of uncertainty, leaving viewers with the uneasy feeling that perhaps you cannot trust your thoughts or your senses. Whether we hear that haunting cry as one of defiance, futility, or madness, this devastating film of Hu Bo is a cry that cannot be unheard.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Parasite and the rise of East Asian representation in Hollywood</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/selina.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Parasite and the rise of East Asian representation in Hollywood" /><published>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T04:40:48+02:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/selina</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/issue1/2020/04/28/selina.html">&lt;p&gt;In recent years, East Asian cinema has taken over the world, with hits
such as &lt;em&gt;Crazy Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Train to Busan&lt;/em&gt; receiving both
commercial and critical acclaim. There is, perhaps, no greater
demonstration of this shift in focus than &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt;’s triumphant Best
Picture win at the 92nd Academy Awards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading up to the awards ceremony, Bong Joon Ho’s &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt; was the
underdog, with predictions favouring &lt;em&gt;1917&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Once Upon a Time in
Hollywood&lt;/em&gt; in lieu of the South Korean thriller. But class struggle, a
lovable scrappy family, and fantastic cinematography made it the perfect
storm. &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt; became the first non-English language movie in
cinematic history to win the biggest award of the night, and rightfully
so. However, it didn’t just break records — it also may have truly
changed the way the film industry sees people of East Asian descent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, Hollywood has been absolutely awful in their depictions of
people of colour on screen. From blackface to casting white people for
Asian roles (Mickey Rooney as Mr. Yunioshi in &lt;em&gt;Breakfast at Tiffany’s&lt;/em&gt;
still makes my soul ache), it seems as though Western filmmaking can
only accept representation if it’s on their terms — an Indian bodega
owner here, a Korean doctor there — and this trend continues today.
Yet, despite this, large strides have been made thanks to the numerous
Asian films that have solidified themselves into western public
consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The turn of the century set in motion a period of incredible success for
East Asian filmmaking. &lt;em&gt;In the Mood for Love, Battle Royale,&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon&lt;/em&gt; were all released in the year 2000,
with the latter being nominated for 10 Academy Awards and winning four
of them. These films became recognizable hits all over the globe and
strongly impacted future movies to come (I, for one, am still not
convinced that the whole dystopian novel/movie craze of the early 2010s
wasn’t influenced by &lt;em&gt;Battle Royale&lt;/em&gt;). Not only were these films great
on their own, but their collective release and subsequent success
demonstrated how diverse and unique Asian-lead storylines could be,
without the need to stereotype or typecast. In addition, the visibility
of their victories changed what Asian filmmakers thought they could
achieve in Hollywood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, we see Asian representation almost everywhere: Steven Yeun’s
breakout role on &lt;em&gt;The Walking Dead&lt;/em&gt;, John Cho’s hair-raising thriller
&lt;em&gt;Searching&lt;/em&gt;, heartwarming romcoms like &lt;em&gt;Always Be My Maybe&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;To
All the Boys I’ve Loved Before&lt;/em&gt; film trilogy (still #TeamPeter y’all).
Audiences will no longer accept lazy or tokenistic representation
anymore; we want stories that allow all aspects of our humanity to be
told. Slowly, these films are showing that Asian people can be sci-fi
soldiers, rom-com protagonists, and superheroes — the kind of
portrayals on screen that I dreamed of having as a child. Thanks to
streaming platforms like Youtube, Netflix, and Hulu producing content
without having to go through the red tape of traditional television
networks and production companies, it is easier than ever to have our
voices be heard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people may think that &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt;’s sweeping win at the Academy
Awards might just be a fluke, but I disagree. &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt; and all the
films that have come before it mark a seismic shift in the way East
Asian people should be represented in the entertainment industry — not
by making our stories more digestible, but by being unapologetic about
the culture and the people they represent.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Selina Qing</name></author><category term="issue1" /><summary type="html">In recent years, East Asian cinema has taken over the world, with hits such as Crazy Rich Asians and Train to Busan receiving both commercial and critical acclaim. There is, perhaps, no greater demonstration of this shift in focus than Parasite’s triumphant Best Picture win at the 92nd Academy Awards. Leading up to the awards ceremony, Bong Joon Ho’s Parasite was the underdog, with predictions favouring 1917 or Once Upon a Time in Hollywood in lieu of the South Korean thriller. But class struggle, a lovable scrappy family, and fantastic cinematography made it the perfect storm. Parasite became the first non-English language movie in cinematic history to win the biggest award of the night, and rightfully so. However, it didn’t just break records — it also may have truly changed the way the film industry sees people of East Asian descent. Historically, Hollywood has been absolutely awful in their depictions of people of colour on screen. From blackface to casting white people for Asian roles (Mickey Rooney as Mr. Yunioshi in Breakfast at Tiffany’s still makes my soul ache), it seems as though Western filmmaking can only accept representation if it’s on their terms — an Indian bodega owner here, a Korean doctor there — and this trend continues today. Yet, despite this, large strides have been made thanks to the numerous Asian films that have solidified themselves into western public consciousness. The turn of the century set in motion a period of incredible success for East Asian filmmaking. In the Mood for Love, Battle Royale, and Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon were all released in the year 2000, with the latter being nominated for 10 Academy Awards and winning four of them. These films became recognizable hits all over the globe and strongly impacted future movies to come (I, for one, am still not convinced that the whole dystopian novel/movie craze of the early 2010s wasn’t influenced by Battle Royale). Not only were these films great on their own, but their collective release and subsequent success demonstrated how diverse and unique Asian-lead storylines could be, without the need to stereotype or typecast. In addition, the visibility of their victories changed what Asian filmmakers thought they could achieve in Hollywood. Nowadays, we see Asian representation almost everywhere: Steven Yeun’s breakout role on The Walking Dead, John Cho’s hair-raising thriller Searching, heartwarming romcoms like Always Be My Maybe and the To All the Boys I’ve Loved Before film trilogy (still #TeamPeter y’all). Audiences will no longer accept lazy or tokenistic representation anymore; we want stories that allow all aspects of our humanity to be told. Slowly, these films are showing that Asian people can be sci-fi soldiers, rom-com protagonists, and superheroes — the kind of portrayals on screen that I dreamed of having as a child. Thanks to streaming platforms like Youtube, Netflix, and Hulu producing content without having to go through the red tape of traditional television networks and production companies, it is easier than ever to have our voices be heard. Some people may think that Parasite’s sweeping win at the Academy Awards might just be a fluke, but I disagree. Parasite and all the films that have come before it mark a seismic shift in the way East Asian people should be represented in the entertainment industry — not by making our stories more digestible, but by being unapologetic about the culture and the people they represent.</summary></entry></feed>